# **JUSTIN HENRY FLORES**

#### CONTACT

**Phone**: (951) 500-3676

Email: Justin.H.Flo@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

- Intermediate with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, React, and Node.js
- Intermediate with Python,
  Django, Java, Spring Boot, PHP,
  MySQL, Git, and JSON
- Novice with JQuery and XML
- Clear Understanding of REST API, DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes, and Relational Database Concepts
- Advanced Analytical and Problem Solving Skills
- Efficient and Good Time Management
- Excellent Verbal and Written Communication
- Proficient with Zoom, Agile, Jira, and Scrum
- Clear Understanding of Regression Analysis and A/B Testing
- Fast Learner
- Self Starter

#### WEBSITE

https://justin-h-flo.github.io/Website

#### **CERTIFICATES**

#### IBM Full Stack Software Developer

https://coursera.org/share/b9de1c4c16106ec9a01f11803e5fd021

#### **Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate**

https://www.credly.com/badges/d4ef2634-36b5-43f8-af4a-9ad12ca41118/public url

#### **Python for Everybody**

https://coursera.org/share/11ec97dfe5bbf130b0beaaf64db468cd

#### Java as a Second Language

https://coursera.org/share/e88132a91ae3ce6028294c5c1fc8494f

#### Agile with Atlassian Jira

https://coursera.org/share/23efccae58f1fe756ae48cb82bc619c3

#### **Wharton's Business Analytics Specialization**

https://coursera.org/share/7bc912b714cd889f366ccce81c6f3a20

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

My MacREU research internship was a paid summer internship that was funded by a National Science Foundation (NSF) award. I had the opportunity to work full time for 10 weeks on a research project. All of the students had the chance to do team building exercises which allowed us to develop our interpersonal skills. I also had the chance to present my work at the North American Solid State Chemistry Conference.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts: Neuroscience

#### University of California, Riverside - Riverside, CA

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# **Delivery Driver,** 06/2020 to Current **Doordash**

- Communicated customer complaints, requests and feedback to company management for swift resolution.
- Fostered positive working relationships with regular customers.
- Completed rush deliveries on tight timetables to satisfy customer needs.

### Researcher, 10/2021 to 05/2022 University Of California, Riverside - Riverside, CA

- Collaborated with colleagues on a scientific publication.
- Conducted research into topics to provide valuable contributions.
- Interpreted and analyzed research data to draw conclusions on outcomes.
- Presented complex scientific topics in an understandable manner.

## Research Assistant, 07/2018 to 03/2020 University Of California, Riverside - Riverside, CA

- Proficient with working in a glove box with a nitrogen atmosphere while performing exceptional synthetic work with chemicals. As well as sealing quartz tubes with a torch.
- Collaborated with colleagues on a scientific publication.
- Analyzed powder and single crystal X-ray diffraction data.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Ortner, T. S., Scheifers, J. P., Flores, J., Zhang, Y., Iyer, A. K., Gesing, T. M., & Fokwa, B. P. (2019). An old dog with new tricks – additions to the cesium lithium chloride system: Cs3Li2Cl5 and the hydrated Cs3LiCl4·4H2O. European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry, 2019(30), 3526–3535. https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.201900774

Scheifers, J. P., Flores, J. H., Janka, O., Pöttgen, R., & Fokwa, B. P. (2022). Triangular arrangement of ferromagnetic iron chains in the high-Tc ferromagnet TiFe1–xOs2+xB2. Chemistry – A European Journal, 28(42). https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202201058